Email: david.j.bramwell@googlemail.com

Website: https://dbramwell.github.io/

DAVID BRAMLER

Summary

I've been working in engineering for the past 12 years and have a wide range of experience, having also had roles in Dev OPS and QA automation as well as pure development roles.

Currently working with Python and Javascript, however in the past I have had commercial experience using Ruby, Java, Groovy, PHP and others, as well as lots of exposure to various Linux flavours and bash scripting.

I approach new development projects with ease of testing and deployment as a primary focus. I currently prefer my local dev environment to be provisioned with Docker Compose, Selenium for browser driven, full stack testing and the AWS CDK for writing infrastructure as code. I have been an AWS certified developer and have experience across many AWS services.

In my spare time I like to contribute to open source. A list of my open source contributions can be found at https://dbramwell.github.io. Early into my learning of ReactJS I started a project called react-animate-on-scroll (https://dbramwell.github.io/react-animate-on-scroll/) which has become popular although is a bit dated now and could probably benefit from a rewrite! I've also written two android games, one in Android/Java, the other using Javascript and React-Native.

Previous Employment

Sponge - Senior Software Developer

September 2020 - Current

Python, Django, VUE js, Terraform, Kubernetes, GCP, CDK, AWS, Docker, Github Actions, PSQL

As well as mentoring junior developers and championing CI and QA automation, I am also the lead developer of Sponge's flagship Learning Management System. Written using Django and Vue, deployed in a Kubernetes cluster in GCP and with unit and E2E tests, my responsibilities include:

- Working on new features and bug fixes to move the platform forward while addressing technical debt.
- Redesigned the development process to focus on building quality in, adding automated unit and E2E tests as well as provisioning of an isolated test environment per pull request.
- Liaising with product owners on the business direction we want to take the system in, which new features would be beneficial to our clients and end users, etc.
- Partaking in agile ceremonies with the team to break down high level features into fully refined stories ready to be put into sprints.

Endemol Shine Group - Full Stack Developer/Technical Lead

June 2018 - September 2020

Javascript, Typescript, ReactJS, PHP, AWS, CDK, Amplify, Cypress, FFMPEG, MYSQL, Docker

Lead developer of a Training Platform as well as a key developer on Endemol's Media Asset Management (MAM) system, both of which utilized a large number of serverless and server based AWS services. I held responsibility for key architecture decisions and mentored newer members of the team. I also instilled best practices such as code reviews, automated testing and infrastructure as code into the development lifecycle of all applications.

Comprehensive Care - Full Stack Developer

6 month contract in New Zealand while on a 2 year backpacking trip June 2017 - December 2017

Javascript, Ruby on Rails, Angularjs, Jenkins, MS SQL

Lead developer of an asthma treatment recommendation application, built on Rails and Angularjs. Ran workgroups on best practices and championed addition of unit tests and automated deployments across all applications.

UBS Investment Bank - Developer

February 2016 - July 2016

Javascript, BackboneJS, Grails, Java, Groovy, Gradle, Maven, Teamcity, Oracle SQL

Working in a cross-functional scrum team of 6. Working across a suite of 10 Java applications and 1 Grails application as well as maintaining and improving the CI pipeline. All our work was done following agile processes with two week sprints, regular backlog grooming and utilising TDD.

UBS Investment Bank - Dev-Ops Engineer

April 2013 - February 2016

Gradle, Maven, Java, Groovy, Teamcity, Bash, RHEL, Javascript, Oracle SQL

Part of a 5 person team responsible for providing developer enablement for around 80 developers and automating the build and deployment processes of 10 applications.

Betfair - QA automation engineer

November 2011 - March 2013

Groovy, Java, Selenium Webdriver, Maven, Jenkins

Responsible for automating the manual test library.

Qualifications

- BSC Degree in Mathematics from Nottingham University
- A-Levels:
 - \circ Maths A
 - ∘ Further Maths A
 - Chemistry C
- GCSEs: 11 A* to C